JACOB ALSPAW

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Versatile and motivated software engineer with 5 years of experience in industry as a full-stack developer. Seeking position that will use my engineering / design skills to add significant creativity, talent, and professional service to company ventures.

jacob.alspaw@case.edu

(636) 699-7344

Littleton, Colorado **Q**

jacob-alspaw.com 1

linkedin.com/in/jacob-alspaw in

EXPERIENCE

MAY 2019 - PRESENT

FRONT-END LEAD & FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER, IBM URBANCODE, HCL SOFTWARE

- Manages the efforts of the front-end development team responsible for producing, maintaining, and modifying web
 front-end code for two major DevOps software product offerings through IBM and HCL Software
- Ensures that correct content, product assortments, and UI functionality is developed, tested, scheduled, and validated against business expectations before it is released to clients
- Solves complex design problems to maximize user experience through collaboration with design teams
- Reduced known UI defects in product backlog by over 90% in less than 10 months to improve client relations
- Collaborated as part of an international support team with IBM and HCL engineers to maintain company relations and meet SLA on issues that impact millions of dollars in financial investments

MAY 2016 - AUGUST 2018

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN, POINTE BLANK SOLUTIONS

- Developed an enterprise suite of web applications that streamlines the justice process and integrates law enforcement agencies, prosecutors, courts and defense attorneys in fifty plus counties across Ohio
- Routinely performed full-stack feature development and system maintenance using C#, SQL Server databases, ASP.NET MVC, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Typescript, jQuery, KnockoutJS, both server-side and client-side rendering systems, code ownership paradigms, automated deployment systems, version control systems such as Git and Mercurial Hg, and mass integration / unit testing

AUGUST 2018 - MAY 2019

PROJECT FOUNDER & LEAD ENGINEER, CWRUded

- Designed and developed a data-driven web service (NodeJS, MongoDB, React), and iOS mobile application with senior university faculty that computed and conveyed real-time "busyness" metrics for various locations around campus
- Solution leveraged address resolution protocol (ARP) and Cisco Prime Infrastructure API that manages CWRU wireless network to expose and aggregate unique active clients connected to wireless access points throughout campus
- Planned and lead meetings with campus deans, network admins, and IT marketing team to bring service to students

APRIL 2015 - FEBUARY 2016

PROJECT MANAGER & LEAD DEVELOPER, LYGENT

- Served as project manager and lead developer of a novel vision screening tool (iStrab™) intended for the measurement of strabismus in children, a treatable disorder in which the eyes become misaligned
- Awarded \$25,000 grant from the Innovation Fund to continue development of the iStrab™ diagnostic equipment
- Project is closely associated with University Hospital's eye clinic and CWRU, and was pending FDA clearance in 2016

EDUCATION

MAY 2019

B.S. in COMPUTER SCIENCE, CASE WESTERN RESERVE UNIVERSITY

- Degree Path: B.S. in Computer Science with a focus in Software Engineering
- Major GPA: 3.634 / 4.0
- Relevant coursework: object-oriented programming, systems programming, algorithms, databases, systems security and networks, discrete mathematics, data structures, software design techniques and craftmanship, mobile application development, programming language concepts, team organization and project management

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, C#, Swift, C++, SQL, NoSQL, HTML5, CSS3, React, Angular, Graphql, Apollo, Qt, MATLAB, Node, ASP.NET MVC, Git, Mercurial, Yarn, npm, Photoshop, Agile, Scrum, DevOps, CI/CD, TDD, Jira, Jenkins, SalesForce

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Strong work ethic
- Dependable
- Positive attitude
- Team oriented
- Self-motivated
- Flexible
- Forward thinker
- Effective communicator